Listen to a talk in an environmental science class.
Biomimicry is the human practice of learning from and imitating things found in nature
in order to create new inventions.
This way, scientists and engineers can create innovative solutions that are both efficient and sustainable.
One well-known example of biomimicry is the development of a widely used fastening system.The
inventor was inspired by the way burrs, uh thorns, from plants stuck to his dog’s fur.
By replicating the tiny hooks found on the burrs he removed from the dog
fur, he created the new fastening system.
Another example is the design of energy-efficient buildings based on the ventilation system of
structures created by termites.
Termites are ground-dwelling insects that use different materials to create hills,
or mounds, in which the termites live.Termite mounds have a complex network of vents.The
vents maintain a stable internal temperature,
which can be emulated in human architecture.
Termite mounds have a complex network of vents.The vents maintain a stable internal
temperature,
which can be emulated in human architecture.
Biomimicry can also be applied to renewable energy.For instance, researchers are developing wind turbine
blades modeled after the flippers of humpback whales.
The unique shape of the flippers reduces drag and increases efficiency, leading to more
effective wind energy capture.